<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case for making the rivers Aire and Calder in the county of York navigable to Leeds and Wakefield</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B42104</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">688634668</idno>
  <idno type="VID">211851</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248537022</idno>
  
            <idno type="OCLC"> 688634668</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocn 688634668</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C865B</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B42104)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 211851)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2990:6)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case for making the rivers Aire and Calder in the county of York navigable to Leeds and Wakefield</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Sutro Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Waterways --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Inland navigation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Inland water transportation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Aire River (England)</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Calder, River (West Yorkshire, England)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="case">
            <pb facs="tcp:211851:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:211851:2"/>
            <head>THE CASE For Making the Rivers AIRE and CALDER, in the County of YORK, Navigable to LEEDS and WAKEFIELD.</head>
            <p>THAT there now is, and for many Years past has been, a very great Trade carried on in the Manufacture of Woollen Cloth, and other Merchandizes and Commodities, from the Towns of <hi>Leeds</hi> and <hi>Wakefield, Hallifax, Ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, Keighley, Burstal, Bradford Bingley, Otley, Skipton, Huddersfield, Peninston, Houley, Horbury, Almondbury, Dewsbury, Mirfield,</hi> and many other Towns in the West Riding of the County of <hi>York,</hi> and <hi>Ratchdale</hi> and <hi>Colne</hi> in the County of <hi>Lancaster;</hi> which Trade is very Advantageous to His Majesty's Customs, and very Beneficial to His Majesty's Subjects, many Thousands of Families being thereby maintained, who without it are not able to subsist.</p>
            <p>BUT, by reason the Traders from the said Places are forced to carry their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities, some Twenty, some Thirty, and others Forty Miles, before they come to a Navigable River, which is extreamly Expensive, and attended with very great Damages to the Goods sent down. This Trade is much hindred, and the High-ways mightily damaged, and the Country put to a great Expence to Repair the same, and notwithstanding such Repairs, yet the Ways are made altogether impassable in Winter-time for ordinary Country Carts and Carriages, by reason of the great number of Carriages, to the great Prejudice of that Country.</p>
            <p>THAT the making of these Rivers Navigable, which are proposed to be done no otherwise than by a Voluntary Contribution of the Neighbouring Towns, Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men and Freeholders, will not only mightily Encourage and Increase Trade in the Northern Parts, and especially that of the Woollen Manufacture, by a more easie and cheap conveyance of Wooll, and all other Commodities that are made use of in the said Manufacture.</p>
            <p>BUT will also preserve the High-ways, and keep them from being at any time impassable, and save much Money laid out in Repairing the same.</p>
            <p>IT will likewise advance His Majesty's Customs, and increase Watermen and Boat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, and consequently Seamen.</p>
            <p>IT will Employ a great many Persons in making the same Navigable, and when made, a great number of Men, Boats, and Horses.</p>
            <p>WHEREFORE it is Humbly hoped, That this Undertaking will have the Assistance and Encouragement of this Honourable House, for the Effecting of so good a Work, and which so highly conduces to the Benefit of the Publick; And to the removing of those great Inconveniencies which the said Country and Traders in the Woollen Manufacture labour under, by reason of their great Distance from a Navigable River.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>